<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-27T18:58:33+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Instinct Wedding - Kent based wedding photography and video team, producing beautiful, documentary style wedding photography and films. Covering Kent, London, East Sussex, Surrey and surrounding areas.</title><subtitle>Instinct Wedding offers photography and videography packages for couples, getting married in Kent, London, East Sussex, Surrey and surrounding areas. We are a husband and wife team, specialising in natural, documentary, candid style, emotional wedding photos and videos. Contact us to arrange a free, non-obligatory consultation.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Our wedding story: how we planned a perfect micro wedding in two months</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/06/our-wedding-story-how-we-planned-a-perfect-micro-wedding-in-two-months.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our wedding story: how we planned a perfect micro wedding in two months " /><published>2020-04-06T13:14:07+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-06T13:14:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/06/our-wedding-story-how-we-planned-a-perfect-micro-wedding-in-two-months</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/06/our-wedding-story-how-we-planned-a-perfect-micro-wedding-in-two-months.html">&lt;p&gt;Just like every bride out there, I think that our wedding was the most exciting, amazing, memorable and fun and that’s why I would love to share our wedding day story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Lloyd and I were engaged for about 7 months (that’s a story for another day), and sometimes we would sit and think, what sort of wedding we would like… sometime in a couple of years, maybe. But never really settling with any plan, or even a date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, one sunny May day, a couple of days after my birthday, we found out I was pregnant with our first baby. I knew, it’s a norm to wait a few weeks to tell people, but I told one of my best friends straight away. She started screaming, singing and looked like the most excited person in the universe for about 45 minutes whilst we were driving by the sea. As we got to the sea, she asked if we still planned to get married. oh, yeah, I said. It would be cool to get married before the baby is born. So I took my phone out and texted Lloyd ‘Hey, do you wanna get married this summer?’ he replied ‘yeah, okay’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8333_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lloyd and Justina on the Seven Sister Cliffs in East Sussex after their wedding ceremony&quot; title=&quot;Bride and Groom on the Seven Sisters Cliffs &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is how we decided to get married. As you can imagine, when you’re a wedding photographer, your schedule is pretty intense in the summer but we had one weekend free in July. So it was decided - it was going to be that free weekend in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started dreaming of locations. It took about 3 minutes to decide on Seven Sisters Cliffs in East Sussex. This is a place, that we love, it’s stunning, it’s not too far. and it’s free. As you can imagine, when you decide to get married in a couple of months, the budget can be a bit tricky. we had zero savings for the wedding. we had zero savings in general, for that matter (this was still the time, when we would happily spend all our income on gigs, trips, air b’n’b’s, good food and going out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after, we shared the plans to get married with Lloyd’s family (together with the announcement, that they will be first time grandparents too). I just loved the enthusiasm and they offered to have the party in their back garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guest list was a tricky one but we knew we wanted to keep it to the absolute minimum and only invite people that we absolutely loved, were close to, who were actively involved in our lives, and we knew would carry on being involved. This was really important for both of us to feel completely, freely, weirdly ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total was 17 people including children. Perfect number!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planning was super easy. We booked a registry office ceremony for two days before our wedding day. Normally, the waiting list is quite long, but as I was pregnant, and they just had a cancellation, we got super lucky to get a day two days before ‘the real wedding’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So grateful that Lloyd’s parent’s let us have the reception in their back garden and they were full of ideas and inspiration. At this point, the first semester of pregnancy was kicking hard. Even though, I always was in a good spirits, I preferred to be in good spirits on the sofa, and going to sleep between 6.30 and 7.30pm, after watching about 10-15 minutes of Netflix before my eyes would be too heavy. Lloyd’s mum created a Pinterest board. I loved every idea she had for this low key, bohemian micro wedding. Lloyd’s sister’s boyfriends mum, who we have never even met, offered to do a vegan wedding cake. I ordered a dress online. It was way too small, so I ordered another one. And that was it. The planning was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8684-2_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home made vegan cake with summer fruits &quot; title=&quot;vegan wedding cake &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day itself was special. Although, in the morning, I woke up angry af. Third month of being pregnant, hit the emotions hard. I decided (on the morning), that I don’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; want to get married. My friends asked me to reconsider. So I reconsidered and decided to I &lt;em&gt;actually do want&lt;/em&gt; to get married. Thankfully that was the only hiccup of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have bridesmaids, but I had my friends with me, who did my hair, make up, helped me decide on the bracelet. They even tied a tiny picture of my mum who passed away on a sunflower (a.k.a. my wedding bouquet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we all drove to the Seven Sisters Cliffs. Lloyd and our wedding party were waiting on the hill, while my brother and my little nephew walked me up the hill (with a couple of stops to catch the breath, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8247_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lloyd waiting for Justina on the seven sisters cliff on the wedding day&quot; title=&quot;Groom waiting &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ceremony was perfect. We took our time, paced it the way we felt was right. We exchanged our vows and I think it was my favourite part of the day. When Lloyd was reading his vows to me, promising things that felt real and heartfelt. I love, that both of us, made vows not only to each other, but also to our daughter in my tummy. We made vows to encourage each other, to be there for each other. And absolutely nothing we weren’t sure we could keep. It was a declaration. Stating the obvious, but with witnesses. With our closest and dearest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8275_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exchanging vows with the closest people at our micro wedding on the seven sister cliffs &quot; title=&quot;reading our personal wedding vows &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hanging out in this spectacular location, we had a few photos, went to dip our feet in the sea, and headed to our parents-in-law garden for the wedding reception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/38250015_10211723689319372_9173251602461491200_n-1-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Just married, enjoying the romantic view of the seven sister cliffs &quot; title=&quot;just married on the seven sister cliffs &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wedding reception at Lloyd’s parents garden was amazing. They did an incredible job to turn the garden into a place that looked ‘just like from Pinterest’ as one of my friends noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were all sitting outside on the grass, sipping non alcoholic beer, eating burgers that Lloyd’s dad cooked on the BBQ, talking, laughing and it felt good. It felt so good, so real, so us. I felt so connected with all the people there. And it felt so special knowing, that this is how our first hours of being married are going, that our daughter was also there, even though still inside my body, celebrating with us. It was so nice to have the most awkward first dance, to see beautiful golden hour. And be done by 7pm. Which, in fact, was already past my three months pregnant bed time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8728-2_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a group hug dance &quot; title=&quot;dance at our micro wedding &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you know what is the best part? Is that our lives as a married couple, are still very much like our wedding day. We do what we love. With the people we love. We only promise what we can keep. And we create our own rules to create the life we feel proud living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8339_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black and white photo of Justina and Lloyd after their wedding &quot; title=&quot;Justina and Lloyd after the wedding ceremony&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to see more photos from our micro wedding day, click here to follow this &lt;a href=&quot;https://instinctwedding.pic-time.com/-justinalloydwedding/gallery&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you would like to have a micro wedding, but don’t know where to start, or have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instinctwedding.com/#contact&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe and inspired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;j. xx&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Just like every bride out there, I think that our wedding was the most exciting, amazing, memorable and fun and that’s why I would love to share our wedding day story!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Covid-19 and your 2020 wedding advice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/15/covid-19-and-your-2020-wedding-advice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Covid-19 and your 2020 wedding advice" /><published>2020-03-15T10:19:39+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T10:19:39+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/15/covid-19-and-your-2020-wedding-advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/15/covid-19-and-your-2020-wedding-advice.html">&lt;p&gt;I thought it’s about time to address the major topic of today and talk about Corona virus. If you’re getting married in 2020, you have probably wondered if and how it’s going to affect your wedding plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first---dont-panic-we-are-all-in-this-together&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First - don’t panic! We are all in this together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our perspective, we do what we can not to catch the virus so we can attend and shoot every single wedding we have booked. We are following governments advice and taking extra precaution by avoiding public places where many people are gathering, and of course - washing our hands often, making sure we’re not touching our faces, we have also decided that air kisses, elbow bumps and even a simple wave are pretty great alternatives to handshake or a hug! Of course, no one is really protected and if we do get infected, we can ensure you that we won’t just ignore the virus and turn up anyway to infect you and your guests. We surely have a plan B and C and feel so liberated about the fact many photographers and videographers from the wedding industry have come together and have created ‘emergency call’ lists, so shall we fall ill, and your wedding is still on, we will ask our super awesome usual second shooter friends to cover your wedding, and even if that plan fails, we have a contact list of other professionals who are keen on helping out. We surely aim not to leave your day uncovered! And of course, we will keep on making sure we are staying as healthy as a radish! (this is Lithuanian saying, which means as healthy as it can be, if your wondered :) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s talk about different options -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;postponement&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postponement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, for whatever reason you decide to postpone your wedding - be it a government advice or a strict ban, you feel symptomatic, you are worried about your guests health, you or your loved ones can’t travel or you simply feel safer moving the date - we do and will work with you to try and reschedule your big day to a different date either later in the year, or next year. All monies you have paid already will be carried over to a new date. This seems to be a common practice and hopefully most suppliers will work on the same or similar terms to make sure that we can transfer your wedding date to a new date as stress free as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to go this route, let us know and we will share our calendar dates and hopefully we can find a suitable date for all your suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/matt-and-jen-wedding-penshurst-place-0382.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bride - covid 19 advice for couples getting married in 2020&quot; title=&quot;bride&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downsizing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downsizing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option if to downsize your wedding, or even opt for an elopement. We definitely think it’s a good idea that your friends and family most at risk stay at home. Of course, it is hard for them and for you, but we strongly believe that health is the most important thing we have. Even if you do decide to downsize or elope, you can still book a restaurant or a lovely pub dinner with people you want to celebrate your marriage but feel would be at risk if attended your big wedding. You can organise this dinner when it all calms down and you can even bring your wedding videos and photos to the dinner to share with them and tell them all about your wedding day. Of course, it may not be ideal, but we have to work around the situation we have and why not try and make the best out of not so great situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/lewis-and-beka-0512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;couple in the fields - corona virus advice for couples getting married in 2020&quot; title=&quot;romantic couple in the wild fields - black and white photography&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;going-on-as-planned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going on as planned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to go on as planned, our advice is not to ignore the virus completely and be considerate to your loved ones. How about leaving hand sanitisers, extra tissues and even anti-bacterial wipes in the bathroom for everyone to use. Also consider that instead of hugs and kisses you bow, wave, elbow bump, feet bump or create your very own greeting gesture. You may even want to spend this time crafting an email to all your guests, explaining the situation and encouraging them to carry on with the government’s advice how to stay healthy and avoiding catching the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/charlotte-and-james-at-george-in-rye-236.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;black and white confetti photo - covid-19 advice for 2020 weddings&quot; title=&quot;confetti photo wedding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;see-good-even-in-a-bad-situation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See good, even in a bad situation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said this at the beginning of this post, and would like to say this again, we are all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So try not to worry and try and see the positives instead. Perhaps if you’re, like us, avoiding public spaces and not going out as much, see it as an opportunity to spend more time with your partner, talk more, cook nice dinner together, have a romantic evening with candles, have a pic-nic in bed, play some board games, read books under one blanket, get creative - have a photoshoot together, paint, draw, look after your plants. Most most importantly - stay healthy and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, please feel free to contact us at any time if you want to chat or if we can answer any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;j.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I thought it’s about time to address the major topic of today and talk about Corona virus. If you’re getting married in 2020, you have probably wondered if and how it’s going to affect your wedding plans.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Location inspiration guide for couple and engagement sessions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/10/location-inspiration-guide-for-couple-and-engagement-sessions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Location inspiration guide for couple and engagement sessions" /><published>2020-03-10T13:54:36+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T13:54:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/10/location-inspiration-guide-for-couple-and-engagement-sessions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/10/location-inspiration-guide-for-couple-and-engagement-sessions.html">&lt;p&gt;To make life easier for our lovely couples, looking to have their engagement session in Kent or East Sussex, where we have listed a few of our favourite and super photogenic locations for you to choose from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, have you seen our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instinctwedding.com/2019/05/20/engagement-session.html&quot;&gt;Engagement Session Guide&lt;/a&gt;, where we talk all about pre-wedding sessions and why we think it’s something every couple should consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for now, let’s dive in and talk about some of our favourite locations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;villages-and-old-towns-in-kent-and-east-sussex&quot;&gt;Villages and old towns in Kent and East Sussex&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we love shooting in villages and old towns is how diverse pictures can turn out. England has got some truly beautiful, unique villages and towns in the East, and we love exploring them with our couples and finding charming spots for photos. What can be a better way to spend a golden hour than wondering around, chatting, and stopping when and as inspiration for a great shot hits. Some of our favourite villages and small towns in the South East England include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rye&quot;&gt;Rye&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A truly unique town, near the coast in East Sussex. That’s where true old English charm is exposed in the beautiful cobbled lanes like Mermaid Street, and English history is hiding in half-timbered houses, which serve as a beautiful, unique and rich background for romantic photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/erika-and-neil-camber-sands-and-rye-engagement-_-instinct-wedding-076_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;couple engagement photography at cobbled mermaid street in Rye&quot; title=&quot;couple walking down Mermaid Street in Rye&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loose&quot;&gt;Loose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loose is situated just outside Maidstone and is an incredibly charming little village. Right in the middle of it, you will find the Brooks Path - picturesque causeway along the Loose Stream that joins the two ends of the village. We love meeting our couples at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theloosechequers.com/&quot;&gt;Chequers inn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theloosechequers.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;for a drink before heading out for a little adventure, capturing photos in a natural and peaceful environment that Loose has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/instinct-wedding-3_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;couple pre wedding photography of couple laughing in loose kent, couple photoshoot location, romantic photography&quot; title=&quot;happy couple laughing by Loose Stream.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/instinct-wedding-31_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Couple photoshoot during golden hour, romantic photography in Kent countryside &quot; title=&quot;Fun and romantic couple during the golden hour in Kent &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rochester&quot;&gt;Rochester&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A historic town, which was among the favourites for Charles Dickens. And there’s a reason for that. We love starting our photoshoots by the Rochester Castle, enjoying the picturesque views and then heading to grab a coffee, or carry on with the photos in one of its charming streets. It’s certainly a town full of amazing opportunities for photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/adam-jola-rochester-engagement-session-instinct-wedding-079_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;black and white photo of a couple kissing outside Rochester Castle&quot; title=&quot;Couple photo session outside Rochester Castle &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-beautiful-outdoor-and-countryside&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The beautiful Outdoor&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and countryside&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love nature and truly believe that no man can create anything greater, more beautiful and perfect than nature can. Living in the South East part of the UK, we feel blessed by how many truly breathtakingly gorgeous spots you can find around. Especially if you’re up for waking up really early to witness the sunrise or are willing to hang out till the sunset, some magical moments are definitely in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our favourite nature backdrops include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seven-sisters&quot;&gt;Seven sisters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal favourite by far! It’s a series of chalk cliffs by the English channel. It’s the sort of place that wherever you look is beautiful. No wonder, Lloyd and I have picked this incredible place to get married ourselves! And you can read all about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instinctwedding.com/2020/04/06/our-wedding-story-how-we-planned-a-perfect-micro-wedding-in-two-months.html&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/img_8538_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;romantic photo backdrop at seven sisters cliffs. Instinct Wedding Justina and Lloyd&quot; title=&quot;Justina and Lloyd - Instinct Wedding team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;camber-sands&quot;&gt;Camber Sands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camber Sands is a beach in East Sussex, and we believe definitely the most photogenic one. Its sand dunes look magnificent in any weather and at any season. I also love, that it’s always a sense of surprise when you choose a beach location for the pre-wedding session as sea can be so unpredictable, and when it’s sunny one minute, it can turn cloudy and moody the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/erika-and-neil-camber-sands-and-rye-engagement-_-instinct-wedding-100_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Couple in the Camber Sands &quot; title=&quot;Couple in the Camber Sands &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;forests&quot;&gt;Forests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are too many beautiful, mystical and fun woods in the South East to list every individual one here. Great thing about forests, just like towns, it’s easy to find a new story and unique background round every corner. Forests and woods are also perfect for couples who like an outdoor location but don’t like when there’s too many people around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/lucia-and-jay-forest-engagement-session-instinct-wedding-028_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;couple kissing in the woods &quot; title=&quot;couple kissing in the woods &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;parks&quot;&gt;Parks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least in our list are town and city parks. We love parks as it looks different all year round, and even shooting in the same park during different weather or season can look completely different because of the changing nature. Maybe you got a park near you that you love to go for walks to? It could be really special to have your engagement session there as it will be a meaningful reminder of your life before marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/jess-matt-engagement-session-whatman-park-032_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;black and white photo of a couple in Whatman park, Maidstone&quot; title=&quot;Couple in Whatman Park, Maidstone &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-few-last-words&quot;&gt;A few last words…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have listed a few of the spots  that we love and know can help to create some beautiful photos. But to tell you the truth, the most amazing, and important in your engagement session is you two, your love and your relationship. If you feel happy, content and joyful, wherever we go, I can assure we will be able to capture some beautiful photos for you to treasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have an idea for an engagement or a couple’s session? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instinctwedding.com/#contact&quot;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;j.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To make life easier for our lovely couples, looking to have their engagement session in Kent or East Sussex, where we have listed a few of our favourite and super photogenic locations for you to choose from!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons Why You Should Get a Second Photographer / Videographer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/03/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-a-second-photographer-videographer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons Why You Should Get a Second Photographer / Videographer" /><published>2020-03-03T13:26:31+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-03T13:26:31+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/03/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-a-second-photographer-videographer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/03/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-a-second-photographer-videographer.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Reasons Why You Should Get a Second Photographer / Videographer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to have completely stress-free photography and video experience, second photographer/videographer is a bonus that you will certainly be glad you chose to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are Instinct Wedding’s 5 reasons why you should get a second photographer / videographer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1--getting-ready&quot;&gt;1 . Getting Ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of times, bride and groom will be getting ready in separate locations, often quite a few miles away from each other. Getting two photographers/videographers will help to ensure that both of your mornings will be captured, without having to worry if we are missing an important or a beautiful moment. Having two shooters will help to ensure that one of us can follow each of you all day. And wouldn’t you want to see your partner getting all excited/nervous as they prepare to marry you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/charlotte-and-james-at-george-in-rye-181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Groom getting ready with his best man &quot; title=&quot;groom getting ready with his best man on the wedding day morning &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2--arriving-at-the-venue&quot;&gt;2 . Arriving at the venue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are getting ready close to each other, having a second shooter will enable us to capture arrival of your guests, their reactions of first seeing your venue, perhaps greeted by your other half. Just another thing that you can’t see on the day, but you can watch back after you receive your wedding photos/video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/matt-and-jen-wedding-penshurst-place-0026_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Groom greeting his aunt at the wedding morning &quot; title=&quot;wedding day morning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3--ceremony&quot;&gt;3 . Ceremony&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having two photographers/videographers will enable us capture multiple emotional moments. Your partner waiting for you, you walking down the isle and your partner’s reaction of seeing you for the first time, your parent’s reactions and your vows… So many emotions are flowing around during the ceremony, and believe us, you will want to remember it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/matt-and-jess-to-edit-_-instinct-wedding-0515_websize.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brides parents at the wedding ceremony&quot; title=&quot;brides parents at the wedding ceremony at winters barn in Canterbury&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4--cocktail-hour&quot;&gt;4 . Cocktail hour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you have your photos taken after the ceremony, another shooter could be capturing your guests enjoying their time. Again something you will not see on the day, but can look back on when you get your photos/video back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-more-memories-and-more-creative-photos&quot;&gt;5. More memories and more creative photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a second photographer/videographer will allow your main shooter to be more creative and look for some more epic, unexpected shots and angles, set up lights for a spectacular night time photo, while the second is still capturing everything that is going on at your reception party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dsc06268.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bride and groom posing outside their wedding venue at great fosters at night time.   &quot; title=&quot;Great fosters wedding photography&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">5 Reasons Why You Should Get a Second Photographer / Videographer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sam + Ryan @ Winding House, Dover, Kent, UK</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/10/Sam+Ryan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sam + Ryan @ Winding House, Dover, Kent, UK" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/10/%20Sam+Ryan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/10/Sam+Ryan.html">&lt;p&gt;Lloyd and I enjoyed every moment capturing Sam &amp;amp; Ryan’s beautiful wedding in Winding House in Dover. Winding House is a former Coal Mining building and is definitely full of charm and uniqueness. As usual we believe, that pictures speak louder than any words, so please watch our latest video and let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/284338083?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venue’s website - www.thewindinghouseweddings.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beautiful flowers by Flowers &amp;amp; Sparkle Weddings - www.flowersandsparkle.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hair and Make Up by RKW Hair - Wedding Hair Stylist twww.rkwair.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video by Instinct Wedding - www.instinctwedding.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you getting married and would like an emotional love film for yourself? Great! We now take bookings for 2019 &amp;amp; 2020. Hurry as dates are filling up fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justina &amp;amp; Lloyd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Lloyd and I enjoyed every moment capturing Sam &amp; Ryan's beautiful wedding in Winding House in Dover.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intimate and Emotional Wedding in stunning Lithuanian countryside | Algirdė + Tomas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/13/Algird%C4%97+Tomas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intimate and Emotional Wedding in stunning Lithuanian countryside | Algirdė + Tomas" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/13/Algird%C4%97+Tomas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/13/Algird%C4%97+Tomas.html">&lt;p&gt;Algirdė and Tomas wedding was a living proof that you don’t need to stay in one venue all day but instead you can go on a day long adventure with all your guests in a mini bus instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With twenty people, the most darling to their hearts, the couple have decided to rent a mini bus and after having their ceremony in the registry house, went to enjoy some beautiful Lithuanian countryside as newly weds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early summer nature had beaten any studio background and everyone enjoyed nice walk in beautiful natural spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, we all went to a lovely villa for wedding dinner, toasts and celebration. One of the most beautiful thing was when we ventured out by the lake in the golden hour, just when the sun started to set and Algirdė and Tomas had their first dance on a bridge, with no music, just them two dancing to the birdsong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, have a look yourself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/279832260?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We absolutely loved travelling for this Wedding and are always super excited to travel to beautiful places for a good wedding. So if you’re getting married tens, hundreds, or even thousand miles from our home in Kent, UK, do not hesitate to contact us and we’d love to chat about your destination wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justina &amp;amp; Lloyd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instinct Wedding Photography and Film&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Algirdė and Tomas wedding was a living proof that you don’t need to stay in one venue all day but instead you can go on a day long adventure with all your guests in a mini bus instead.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Erika &amp;amp; Neil Engagement Session in the moody Camber Sands and Rye</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/19/erika+neil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Erika &amp; Neil Engagement Session in the moody Camber Sands and Rye" /><published>2019-06-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/19/erika+neil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/19/erika+neil.html">&lt;p&gt;Some days are just good days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of days Good Days was a day when I got a pleasure to meet Erika and Neil for their engagement session in Rye. At first we met at a little cafe, called Simon the Pieman and had a chat about their wedding plans (which, by the way, I absolutely love and cannot wait for their wedding by the Scottish loch later this year!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little chat we ventured for a little walk in the beautiful ancient streets of Rye. As it was a nice Sunday afternoon, the streets were quite busy, we decided to drive to the Camber Sands - a beautiful sandy beach just about 10 minutes away from Rye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minute we got out of the car and stepped on the sand, I could see the change in Erika and Neil as they literally lit up and got so excited and playful. You could definitely see that sea, salty air, sand, moody evening sky was completely their element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then on I didn’t even need any of my posing ‘prompts’, everything went so naturally, and oh so beautifully…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just look at this couple &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Erika-and-Neil-Camber-Sands-and-Rye-Engagement-_-Instinct-Wedding-061.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Erika-and-Neil-Camber-Sands-and-Rye-Engagement-_-Instinct-Wedding-093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Erika-and-Neil-Camber-Sands-and-Rye-Engagement-_-Instinct-Wedding-097.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Erika-and-Neil-Camber-Sands-and-Rye-Engagement-_-Instinct-Wedding-107.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Some days are just good days.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nicollette &amp;amp; Mike Engagement Photo Session in St Dunstan-in-the-East in London</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/04/nicollette+mike.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicollette &amp; Mike Engagement Photo Session in St Dunstan-in-the-East in London" /><published>2019-06-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/04/nicollette+mike</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/04/nicollette+mike.html">&lt;p&gt;I got super excited when Nicollette suggested to have her and Mikey’s engagement session in St Dunstan-in-the-East in London. To be honest, I have never heard of this place before but after a quick Google search, I became convinced this was going to be a great spot and an amazing backdrop for some beautiful engagement shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hidden just a few minutes walk away from the ever busy London Bridge, there is this little place of quiet and tranquility. What used to be a Church of England parish church, that got destroyed in the World War II, has now been turned into a public garden with beautiful plants growing freely on the few left standing walls of this old building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After arriving to the park and seeing Nicollette and Mikey waiting in the garden, I got even more excited as the couple looked absolutely beautiful and their outfit choice was absolutely spot on for this location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though, it was a cloudy late Spring evening, Nicollette and Mikey’s smiles and love for each other has really made this session special and beautiful. And we absolutely can’t wait till we get to capture this beautiful couple’s wedding next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Nicollette-and-Mikey-024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Nicollette-and-Mikey-004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Nicollette-and-Mikey-027.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Nicollette-and-Mikey-014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I got super excited when Nicollette suggested to have her and Mikey's engagement session in St Dunstan-in-the-East in London.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ab &amp;amp; Zamani Wedding Highlight Film @ The Conservatory at the Painshill, Cobham, Surrey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/22/ab+zamani.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ab &amp; Zamani Wedding Highlight Film @ The Conservatory at the Painshill, Cobham, Surrey" /><published>2019-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/22/ab+zamani</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/22/ab+zamani.html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/337752806?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ab and Zamani’s wedding day at the Conservatory at the Painshill in Cobham was a great start to the wedding season. Not only was this wedding about Ab and Zamani and their love to each other, but also a beautiful occasion of two families coming together, joining the couple for a day of love, happiness and fun. It was a truly beautiful mix of vibrant colours and joy - full of tradition, tears, laughter, food and so much dancing all the way into the night!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ab and Zamani's wedding day at the Conservatory at the Painshill in Cobham was a great start to the wedding season.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Instinct Wedding’s Engagement Session Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/20/engagement-session.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instinct Wedding's Engagement Session Guide" /><published>2019-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/20/engagement-session</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/20/engagement-session.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-best-out-of-your-engagement-session&quot;&gt;Making the best out of your engagement session&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement sessions are great for two reasons: first, you get a chance to dress up, feel and look your best, whilst celebrating your love as an engaged couple. Secondly, you can look at it as sort of a ‘rehearsal’ photo session before your wedding so you know what to expect from a photo hour at your wedding. For us, photographers, it’s very useful too, as we get to see the dynamics between you as a couple and ensure that the photo hour on your big day goes super smooth and is a complete reflection of you two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said all that, we know that for some couples the thought of an engagement session can still be quite daunting and even stressful, but it really shouldn’t be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s dive in and discuss some points that are worth thinking about before your engagement session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;location&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always suggest to choose location that means something to you. Perhaps a park where you went for your first walk, seaside where you shared your first kiss, or even your very own kitchen where you spend the best time together laughing and baking cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we are also always happy to give some suggestions if you absolutely can’t think of anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super idea: if you really want to make a statement with your engagement session, and you feel that your ideal location is a bit further afield, or even abroad, don’t be shy to tell us! We absolutely love travelling and adventures and with enough notice can arrange anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t want or can’t travel but still want to make a statement with your engagement session locally? We can always use props - from fairy lights in the woods, smoke bombs in a field, or a beautifully styled ‘tea party’ style table in your garden - there is no limits to imagination!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timing&quot;&gt;Timing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to have your session outdoors in nature, we love natural light, and the best and most beautiful time of the day is during the Golden Hour, which happens an hour before the sunset or first couple of hours after the sunrise. If you decide to go for an evening Golden Hour, we suggest meeting up an hour or so earlier, especially if it’s the first time when we meet, so we can have a chat and a coffee, and get comfortable around each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t make it in the morning or evening? No problem!  With a bit of a creative thinking can make even the harsh sun work. Just let us know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;style&quot;&gt;Style&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style is  such an exciting point to think about because it’s literally one occasion where you can dress up, accessorise and look and feel your best. It’s great way to make your personalities really shine through. We suggest you take some time to do your hair, nails and make-up just the way you love. Don’t be shy! You literally cannot overdress for an engagement session. Also, don’t be afraid to use accessories, such as hats, sunglasses, scarves, etc. They not only look great on photos but can also serve as a prop and give a bit of a variety to photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you have a ring you love and you want a photo of that, don’t forget your nails!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top tip: have you thought of scheduling your make-up and hair trial at the day of the engagement session?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matching styles. It’s nice if your and your partner’s outfits are complimenting each other in colour and style. Also, think of the location, if your shoot is in a vibrant city, you may want to choose bolder colours, whereas if you want a romantic session by the sea, earthy, or pastel tones might be a better choice. However, the most important thing is that you feel your best! Oh and did I mention you literally cannot overdress for engagement session?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing outfits. You might want to bring two outfits with you and change mid session which is absolutely cool! Alternatively you can bring a jacket, a cardigan or a scarf that you can take on and off for a bit of a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-note&quot;&gt;Final Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best accessory is your happy eyes and your love for each other! There’s absolutely no need to stress before the engagement session. We always try and make it fun and chilled - a fun time out. We promise to guide you but not force you in any poses that you feel uncomfortable with. We might ask you to talk, walk or play with each other rather than posing awkwardly whilst staring to the camera. So relax and put your smile on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as you will be all dressed up and beautiful already, why not make the best of it and plan a romantic date afterwards?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Engagement sessions are great for two reasons: first, you get a chance to dress up, feel and look your best, whilst celebrating your love as an engaged couple.</summary></entry></feed>